Guide to the Frey Family Papers 1793-1917 (Bulk 1825-1890) MS 235
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1793-1917, undated
  - Subseries 56. Letters sent, H
    - Letters sent: Ha-He (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Hi-Hy (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 57. Ives, Jane, 1873-1877, undated
    Letters from Racine, WI concerning family health, news, deaths.
    - Letters sent: Ives, Jane, 1873-1877 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 58. Johnson, George G., 1854-1862
    Letters to John Frey regarding local news, finances, property sales, limestone, farming, politics, and the impending Civil War. Johnson also discusses his son Alonzo's financial dealings with Frey and his whereabouts in California.
    - Letters sent: Johnson, George G., 1854-1862 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 59. Jones family, 1899-1913, undated
    Letters to Samuel Ludlow Frey of holiday greetings, family news, school and college, and travels. Includes:
    Barbara (1911-1912), Helen [probably Helen Jones Jr.] (1899, 1910), Helen [probably Helen Jones Sr.] (1910-1911),Wallace (1899, 1910-1913, undated).
    - Letters sent: Jones family, 1899-1913, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 60. Letters sent, I-J
    - Letters sent: I-J (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 61. Kane, Elias, 1816-1826
    Letters to Henry I. Frey regarding finances, land sales.
    - Letters sent: Kane, Elias, 1816-1819 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Kane, Elias, 1820-1826 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 62. Knox, Elizabeth, 1838-1876
    Letters discussing local news, deaths (particularly of Caroline Ludlow Frey), health and illness.
    - Letters sent: Knox, Elizabeth, 1838-1876 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 63. Letters sent, K
    - Letters sent: K (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 64. Lathrop, Maria Ludlow, 1825, 1835-1851, 1873
    Letters concerning family news, illnesses, and deaths (especially the death of her mother Phebe Ludlow); also her husband Rev. L.E. Lathrop's leaving his ministerial post.
    - Letters sent: Lathrop, Maria Ludlow, 1825, 1835-1851, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 65. Lathrop family, 1832, 1841, 1875
    Includes: Henry (1841), J.M. (1875), Leonard (1832); 1 item each.
    - Letters sent: Lathrop family, 1832, 1841, 1875 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 66. Ludlow, Anna D., 1862, 1868-1900
    Letters regarding family news, finances, health and illnesses, the death of her mother (1877), and the family vault. Some letters (1873-1875) are written from Savannah and Charlestown, detailing her work as a teacher of African-American children.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Anna D., 1862, 1868-1900 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 67. Ludlow, Ellen, 1873-1900, undated
    Letters written from Oswego, NY, most to John Frey, concerning the family, health, her father, Samuel Baldwin Ludlow, his illness and death (1882); religion and the local church, women and religion, the Beecher scandal; Oswego news, deaths, politics, weather.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Ellen, 1873-1881 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Ellen, 1882-1900, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 68. Ludlow, FitzHugh, 1850-1860, undated
    Letters, most to Samuel Ludlow Frey, detailing family news, school life, opinions on religion, his religious conversion, lecturing stints.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, FitzHugh, 1850-1860, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 69. Ludlow, Helen, 1872-1913, undated
    Letters about family news, reflections on her father, Rev. Henry Gilbert Ludlow; some items written from the Hampton Institute, Va., but do not go into great detail about school life; others written from St. Augustine, FL.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Helen, 1872-1913, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 70. Ludlow, Henry Gilbert, Rev., 1824-1865, undated
    Letters concerning the state of religion in New York City, New Haven, Poughkeepsie, religious instruction, Catholicism, cholera (1832), John Frey's financial troubles, illness and family deaths, death of his mother, Phebe Ludlow (1840), births, his children, love letters to his second wife Maria Tappen (1851).
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Rev. Henry Gilbert, 1824-1836 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Rev. Henry Gilbert, 1837-1848 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Rev. Henry Gilbert, 1851-1865, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 71. Ludlow, Maria Beekman Tappen, 1851
    Love letters to Rev. Henry Gilbert Ludlow, also discussing family and New York City news, FitzHugh Ludlow's future, and wedding plans.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Maria Beekman Tappen, 1851 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 72. Ludlow, Nancy Douglas, 1828-1829, 1872[?], undated
    Letters, most written from Philadelphia, concerning family and local news, religious revivals.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Nancy Douglas, 1828-1829, 1872[?], undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 73. Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1825-1881, undated
    Early letters (through 1831) are written from Philadelphia; from 1836 on, written from Oswego, NY. They discuss family news and troubles, health problems (particularly his eyes), local politics, businesses, including insurance, gas and railroad, politics, Ulysses S. Grant, Roscoe Conkling, racial issues (c1875), the Beecher scandal, his daughter Ellen, the last illness and death of his wife, Nancy Douglas Ludlow (1877), physical ailments.
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1825-1841 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1846-1860 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1865-1872 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1873-1875 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1876-1878 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Ludlow, Samuel Baldwin, 1879-1881, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 74. Ludlow family, others, 1828-1899, undated
    Includes: Ambrose (1828, 1841; 2 items), [Elizabeth (prob., b.1830)] (1855-1856, undated; 5 items), Harry (1899; 1 item), Phebe (undated; 1 item), Rosalie (1860; 1 item), Samuel Baldwin, Jr. ["Baldwin"] (1856-1857; 4 items).
    - Letters sent: Ludlow family, others, 1828-1899, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 75. Letters sent, L
    - Letters sent: L (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 76. Moore, David, 1857-1864
    Letters to John Frey, most written from California, regarding the prospects for California, Frey's financial and legal dispute with Alonzo Johnson and the latter's whereabouts, local news.
    - Letters sent: Moore, David, 1857-1864 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 77. Letters sent, M
    - Letters sent: M (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 78. Letters sent, N
    - Letters sent: N (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 79. Letters sent, O
    - Letters sent: O (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 80. Pruyn, Margaret Van Schaack, 1824-1841
    Letters discussing family news, deaths of various family members.
    - Letters sent: Pruyn, Margaret Van Schaack, 1824-1841 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 81. Letters sent, P
    - Letters sent: P (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 82. Rich, Dexter, 1855, 1858-1862
    Letters about the Frey family farm, cows, planting, and finances.
    - Letters sent: Rich, Dexter, 1855, 1858-1862 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 83. Letters sent, R
    - Letters sent: R (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 84. Silvester, Margaret, 1830-1853, undated
    Letters about family news and deaths.
    - Letters sent: Silvester, Margaret, 1830-1853, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 85. Letters sent, S
    - Letters sent: S (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 86. Letters sent, T
    - Letters sent: T (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 87. Van Schaack, D.[avid], 1821-1868, undated
    Letters, most to John Frey, concerning land sales, financial matters with Frey, family news and deaths.
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack, D.[avid], 1821-1868, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 88. Van Schaack, Henry C., 1836-1873
    Letters about family news and deaths, visits, and Henry Van Schaack Frey's grave in St. Augustine.
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack, Henry C., 1836-1873 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 89. Van Schaack, Peter, 1806-1830, undated
    Letters regarding land, finances, family news, and the death of Henry Van Schaack Frey.
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack, Peter, 1806-1830, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 90. Van Schaack, Peter Jr., 1820, 1832, 1851, 1862, undated
    Letters concerning land, his father's health, family news and health.
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack, Peter Jr., 1820, 1832, 1851, 1862, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 91. Van Schaack, Peter C., 1825-1879
    Letters regarding family news, finances, the deaths of his mother, wife, and Caroline Ludlow Frey, romantic advice to John Frey.
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack, Peter C., 1825-1879 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 92. Van Schaack family, others, 1848-1900, undated
    Includes: Anna (1877; 2 items), Asa (1848; 1 item), Catherine (1877; 2 items), Christina (1 item), David (1900; 2 items), Dorcas (undated; 1 item), John Jay [probably son of David] (1863-1877; 4 items), Peter [son of Henry C.] (1868, 1899; 5 items).
    - Letters sent: Van Schaack family, others, 1848-1900, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 93. Letters sent, V
    - Letters sent: V (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 94. Wagner, P.J., 1839-1873
    Letters to John Frey regarding Frey's finances, national politics, land sales, the Wagner family, the Civil War, Frey's legal matters, foreclosure.
    - Letters sent: Wagner, P.J., 1839-1873 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 95. Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1851-1899, undated ["Carrie," "Sis"]
    On microfilm: Dec. 1874-May 1880, Misc. Reel #61. July 1883-July 1887, Misc. Reel #19.
    Letters written from Nebraska (1874-1878) were published in Nebraska History, Spring 1981, pp. 1-46.
    Caroline E. Frey married Col. Grotius R. Giddings in 1862; he died in 1867. She married army surgeon Dr. Charles K. Winne in 1874.
    Chronology of postings:
    1861-1865 Fort Trumbull, CT; New Orleans, LA; Oswego, NY; Palatine Bridge, NY
    1874 Dec.-1877 Nov. Sidney Barracks, NE
    1877 Nov.-1878 Jan. Fort McPherson, NE
    1879 May-1880 May Fort Washakie, WY
    1880 Aug. Fort Brady, MI
    1880 Oct.-1883 Mar. Fort Schuyler, NY
    1883 July-1883 Nov. Fort Winfield Scott, CA
    1883 Dec.-1884 Sept. Angel Island, CA
    1884 Oct.-1885 July Benicia Barracks, CA
    1885 July-1887 July U.S. Arsenal, Benicia, CA
    1887 Sept.-1890 May Fort Wadsworth, Staten Island, NY
    1891 Nov. Fort Snelling, MN
    1899 June Fort Crook, NE
    Early letters detail family news and her first husband's illnesses, and her mother's death (1873). Letters from Nebraska (12/1874-1/1878), describe local Native Americans, a meeting with Sitting Bull (2/13/1875), her husband's family troubles, her pregnancy and difficult childbirth (1875), violent incidents in the frontier town, health and small pox, complaints about army life and servants, the death of Crazy Horse (letter 9/9/1877), the birth of Charles K. Winne Jr. (9/30/1877), her husband's position in the army and his opportunities for reappointment. Letters from 1878 through mid-1883 discuss the baby, the journey to Wyoming, and her health; and contain descriptions of Wyoming, including a Shoshone Sundance (5/25/1879). An eighteen-page letter of 6/17/1883 and postcards detail her transcontinental railroad journey to California. Letters from California contain family news; reports of her son's education; reactions to the deaths of Henry A. Frey and her father, John Frey; descriptions of the weather, local life, numerous post transfers; opinions on the Chinese and Chinese servants (see especially letters of 1/3/1886, 4/19/[1887], 10/9/1887).
    Note: a number of Caroline Frey Winne's undated letters have been tentatively dated, in pencil and in brackets, by a previous processor. The accuracy of these dates has not been verified, and these letters have been moved into the undated folders at the end of the subseries.
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1851-1860 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1861-1863 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1872-1873 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1874 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1875 Jan.-June (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1875 July-Dec (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1877 Jan.-Apr. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1877 May-Aug (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1877 Sept.-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1878 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1879 Jan.-June (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1879 July-Sept. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1879 Oct.-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1880 Jan.-Mar. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1880 Apr.-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1881 Jan.-Apr. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1881 May-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1882 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1883 Jan.-Aug. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1883 Sept.-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1884 Jan.-Apr. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1884 May-Aug. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1884 Sept.-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1885 Jan.-Mar. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1885 Apr.-June (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1885 July-Sept. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1885 Oct.-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1886 Jan.-June (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1886 July-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1887 Jan.-Apr. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1887 May-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, 1898-1899 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, Undated [1872-1881] (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: Winne, Caroline Frey Giddings, Undated [1883-1887] (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 96. Winne, Charles K., 1875-1877, 1886
    Most letters concern Caroline Frey Winne's pregnancy in 1875 and her poor condition following childbirth (baby was stillborn or died soon after). Later letters discuss the birth of Charles K. Winne, Jr. and family matters.
    - Letters sent: Winne, Charles K., 1875-1877, 1886 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 97. Winne, Charles K. Jr., 1886-1911 ["Bopper"]
    Mostly childhood letters about pets, excursions, family, botany. Later letters discuss family visits.
    - Letters sent: Winne, Charles K., Jr., 1886-1911 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 98. Wynkoop, Francis, 1838-1879
    Letters concern John Frey's finances, family matters (both Frey and Wynkoop), mortgages, fishing, and the varnish business.
    - Letters sent: Wynkoop, Francis, 1838-1879 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 99. Letters sent, W
    - Letters sent: W (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 100. Letters sent, Y
    - Letters sent: Y (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 101. Letters sent, unidentified, 1799-1912, undated
    - Letters sent: unidentified, 1799-1859 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Letters sent: unidentified, 1860-1912, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 102. Envelopes and stamps, 1893-1902, undated
    Alienated and blank envelopes; loose stamps.
    - Envelopes; stamps, 1893-1902, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Series II. Diaries, 1821-[18]92, undated
  - Subseries 1. Samuel Ludlow Frey, 1859-1886
    Brief entries in pocket diaries concerning family matters, weather, social events, playing cricket, politics, finances, fishing, botany, Indian relic hunting, and articles written. Most entries simply detail daily farm activities such as plowing and planting.
    - Diaries: Samuel Ludlow Frey (19 volumes), 1859-1886 (Box 17)
  - Subseries 2. Caroline Ludlow [Frey], 1821-1826
    Spiritual diaries. Many are unbound, loose sheets. Only the first of these diaries is signed by Caroline Ludlow [Frey], the rest are assumed to be hers. Entries are reflections on religion and particular sermons.
    - Diaries: Caroline Ludlow [Frey], 1821-1826 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3. [Helen Ludlow], 1860
    Pocket diary probably belonging to Helen Ludlow. Entries detail daily household and social activities, family news, her emotional state, reading, cooking, trips to Niagara and Boston, her father's sermons, and what appears to be an aborted courtship. Notes in the back of the volume include a list of daily chores, poetry, and finances.
    - Diaries: [Helen Ludlow], 1860 (Box 17)
  - Subseries 4. John Frey, 1829-1830
    John Frey's brief travel diary of his excursion to St. Augustine, FL with his ailing brother Henry.
    - Diary: [John Frey], travels to St. Augustine, FL, 1829-1830 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5. Unidentified, 1829-[18]92, undated
    This subseries includes an unidentified author's weather diary for Jan., 1829, an unidentified author's brief travel diary for a trip to Virginia in 1892, and a mostly blank pocket diary of an unidentified author.
    - Diary: unidentified, weather, 1829 Jan. 1-12 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Diary: unidentified, travel diary to Va., 1892 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Diary: unidentified, Undated (Box 17, Folder unknown container)
- Series III. Financial Records, 1799-1912, undated
  This series contains Frey family account books, bills, loose accounts, bonds, promissory notes, receipts, printed reports, and calculations. Sorted by last date on item. Printed reports include insurance company statements and annual reports for the town of Palatine, NY. Account books include two 1863 volumes (possibly belonging to Henry A. Frey) detailing items (alcohol, food, cigars) sold to Union troops.
  - Financial Records, 1799-1821 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1821-1828 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Financial Records, 1829-1832 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1833-1834 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records, 1835-1836 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records, 1837-1844 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records, 1845-1861 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1862-1865 July (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1865 Aug.-1867 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1871-1904 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Financial Records: Calculations and undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records: Printed reports, 1856-1912 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records: Account book, 1812-1837 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records: Account book, 1863 Apr.-Nov. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records: Account book, 1863 Apr.-Sept. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Financial Records: Account book, 1865 Oct. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Legal Material, 1799-1865, undated
  This series includes indentures, bonds, court papers (including copies of opinions), notes, drafts of wills, agreements, estate inventories and papers, notices, articles of agreement. Many of the items concern John Frey's financial and legal troubles, especially the undated material.
  - Legal material, 1799-1842 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Legal material, 1846-1865 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Legal material, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Series V. Land and Property Records, 1806-1873, undated
  Includes surveys, memorandum, records of patent lots, articles of agreement, indentures, and sales of Frey family land. Also one folder of house plans.
  - Land and property records, 1806-1847 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Land and property records, 1849-1873, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Land and property records: house plans, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Series VI. Genealogical Material, undated
  This series includes family trees for the Van Schaack, Ludlow, and Herkimer families, as well as a North family register, and notes on the Herkimer, Yates, and Roach families.
  - Genealogical material, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Poetry, undated
  This series contains copies of published poems, as well as poetry that is most likely original, including FitzHugh Ludlow's "Epistle from a brave of the Ludlow Tribe to a distinguished Mohawk," written for his cousin, Samuel Ludlow Frey.
  - Poetry, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Series VIII. Ephemera, 1818-[1904], undated
  Includes invitations, announcements, and programs for various events including balls, festivals, weddings, meetings, concerts, tournaments, and historical commemorations (including the 1876 centennial and an anniversary celebration of the Emancipation Proclamation at Hampton Institute); an announcement for the sale of the Frey family farm; death notices; advertisements for barbed wire fences, farm machinery, health remedies, wine making paraphernalia; circulars for beehives and globes; direct mail from the Republican State Committee; calling cards; catalogs for an antique auction with notes; and a railroad timetable for the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad.
  - Ephemera: invitations, announcements, programs, 1854-1891, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Ephemera: announcement, sale of Frey farm, 1856 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Ephemera: death notices, 1818, [1873]-1886, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Ephemera: advertisements, 1884, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Ephemera: circulars, direct mail, 1880-1899, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Ephemera: calling cards, Undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Ephemera: auction catalogs, [1904] (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Ephemera: railroad timetable, 1878 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Series IX. Organizational Material, 1880-1911, undated
  This series contains material relating to the meetings of various organizations, including the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Oneida Historical Society, the Scotch-Irish Society of America, and the Daughters of the American Revolution. Also included is the handwritten, undated "Eighth Annual Report of the Female Praying Society."
  - Organizational material, 1880-1911, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Series X. Educational Material, 1833-1857, undated
  This series contains report cards, an achievement certificate for Frey children, and two school notebooks.
  - Report cards, certificate, 1851, 1857, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Ceylina North, "Practical Arithmetic", 1833 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: unidentified [possibly Elizabeth Frey], "Deffinitions," geographical terms, Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Series XI. Drafts, 1799, 1852, undated